...it's no fairy tale.
When the Wind Blows is a animation, war, drama
film directed by Jimmy T. Murakami.
With the help of government-issued pamphlets, an elderly British couple build a shelter and prepare for an impending nuclear
attack, unaware that times and the nature of war have changed from their romantic memories of World War II.
Jim Bloggs (voice), played by John Mills.
Hilda Bloggs (voice), played by Peggy Ashcroft.
Radio Announcer (voice), played by Robin Houston.
Russian submariner (voice), played by James Russell.
Additional Voices (voice), played by David Dundas.
Additional Voices (voice), played by Matt Irving.
When the Wind Blows is a 1986 British apocalyptic adult animated film directed by
Jimmy Murakami based on the 1982 graphic novel by Raymond Briggs.
It stars the voices of John Mills and Peggy Ashcroft as the two
main characters and was scored by Roger Waters.
The film recounts an elderly couple's attempt to survive a nuclear attack and
maintain a sense of normality in fallout and nuclear winter.
The film explores themes of husband wife relationship,
countryside, nuclear war, england, world war ii.
The tone is emotional.